batchblue.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy Statement | Batchbook

BatchBlue Software has created this privacy statement (“Statement”) in order to demonstrate our commitment to customer privacy. Privacy on the BatchBlue Software web site (the “Site”) is of great importance to us. Because we gather important information from our visitors and customers, we have established this Statement as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices. We reserve the right to change this Statement and will provide notification of the change at least thirty (30) business days prior to the change taking effect.

### Information We Collect

A. Information you provide to us: We require customers who register to use the services offered on our Site (collectively, the “Service”) to give us contact information, such as their name, company name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, and financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of users within the organization that will be using the Service. At the time you express interest in obtaining additional information, or when you register for the Service, we may also ask for additional personal information, such as title, department name, fax number, or additional company information, such as annual revenues, number of employees, or industry. Customers can opt out of providing this additional information by not entering it when asked.

B. Hosted and stored Batchbook accounts. When you create or upload your Batchbook account (the “Data”), we have access to the Data in your account.

C. Other Information we receive and store. When you register to use Batchbook, we store “cookies”, which are strings of code, on your computer and they are used to tell us whether customers and visitors have visited the Site previously. Standing alone, cookies do not identify you personally. They merely recognize your browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to BatchBlue Software, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or registering, you remain anonymous to BatchBlue Software. Cookies come in two flavors: session and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you’ve closed your browser or turned off your computer. They include such information as a unique identifier for your browser.

BatchBlue Software uses session cookies containing encrypted information to allow the system to uniquely identify you while you are logged in. This information allows BatchBlue Software to process your online transactions and requests. Session cookies help us make sure you are who you say you are after you’ve logged in and are required in order to use the BatchBlue Software application. BatchBlue Software uses persistent cookies, which only BatchBlue Software can read and use, to identify the fact that you are a BatchBlue Software customer or prior BatchBlue Software Website visitor (whatever the case may be). We are especially careful about the security and confidentiality of the information stored in persistent cookies. For example, we do not store account numbers or passwords in persistent cookies. Users who disable their Web browsers’ ability to accept cookies will be able to browse our Website but will not be able to successfully use our Service.

D. Tracking Cookies or Third Party Cookies. We may from time to time engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from visitors to our website to help us administer our website and improve its quality. Such third parties may use cookies, web beacons or other automated technologies to help track visitor behavior. Such cookies will not be used to associate individual website visitors to any personally identifiable information. All data collected by such third parties on behalf of BatchBlue Software is used only to provide us with aggregate information on site usage. Specifically, BatchBlue partners with Google Analytics to provide us with information on site usage. Google Analytics’ terms are available here: http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html. If you have a concern regarding the use of Google Analytics, you should consult the Google Analytics terms, as BatchBlue has no ability to control or monitor our data analytics partners’ data collection or data use practices.

E. Other Information. BatchBlue Software may also collect certain information from visitors to and customers of the Site, such as Internet addresses. This information is logged to help diagnose technical problems, and to administer our Site in order to constantly improve the quality of the Service. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers and provide such information to third parties.

### Use and Disclosure of Your Information

Except as we explicitly state at the time we request information, or as provided for in the BatchBlue Software End User License Agreement, we do not disclose to third parties the information provided. BatchBlue will use and disclose your Information and Data only as follows:

A. To set up the Service and promote continued use of the Service. We use your Information to set up the Service for you and your organizations. We may also use the Information to contact customers to further discuss customer interest in our company, the Service that we provide, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as promotions and events. Customers are invited to receive an email newsletter by providing an email address. Customer email addresses and any personal customer information will not be distributed or shared with third parties. Customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by sending an email to support@batchblue.com. Separately, customers are also asked to provide an email address when registering for the Service, in order to receive a username and password. We may also email information regarding updates to the Service or company. Again, email will not be distributed or shared and customers can opt out of receiving any communication by emailing support@batchblue.com at the time it is distributed, or at the time any customer registers for the Service.

B. To send you messages about the Service to let you know about temporary or permanent changes to the Service including planned outages, new features offered, version updates, abuse warnings, changes to our Privacy Policy and other documents and agreements.

C. To bill and collect sums owed to us. All financial and billing information that we collect through the Site is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers and to bill for the Service. This billing information is not used by BatchBlue Software for marketing or promotional purposes. BatchBlue Software uses a third-party intermediary to manage the credit card processing. This intermediary is solely a link in the distribution chain, and is not permitted to store, retain, or use the information provided, except for the sole purpose of credit card processing.

D. To help enforce compliance with our BatchBlue End User License Agreement. /eula.html

E. To protect the rights and safety of our company, our employees, our members and users and to meet legal requirements such as complying with court orders and valid subpoenas. BatchBlue reserves the right to share Your Information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law. In exceptionally rare circumstances where national, state or company security may be at issue, BatchBlue reserves the right to share our entire database with appropriate governmental authorities.

F. To communicate with you concerning your account.

G. To transfer your Information in the event of a sale of substantially all of the assets of our business to a third party or in the event of a merger, consolidation or acquisition. However, in any such event, the acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy.

H. Refer a friend. If you elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask you for your friend’s name and email address. BatchBlue Software will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. We do not retain or store this information.

I. Contests and Sweepstakes. We may, from time to time, offer surveys, contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions on our site or through social media (our “Promotions”). Participation in our Promotions is completely voluntary. Information requested for entry may include personal contact information such as your name, address, date of birth, phone number, email address, username, and similar details. We use the information you provide to administer our Promotions. We may also, unless prohibited by the Promotion’s rules or law, use the information provided to communicate with you, or other people you select, about our services. We may share this information with our affiliates and other organizations or service providers in line with this policy and the rules posted for the Promotion.

### Your Batchbook Data

Your Batchbook account is stored on a secure BatchBlue server. We do not contact people in your Batchbook account, or share your Batchbook account with any other party except as required by law, or as you direct us. We do not hold your Batchbook account hostage and we do not make it difficult for you to reclaim them or move them around.

### Third-Party Sites

The Site may contain links to other web sites. BatchBlue Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other web sites. Customers and visitors will need to check the policy statement of these others web sites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential.

### Security

Our Site has security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Data under our control. When our Site is accessed using any modern browser that supports the protocol, Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology protects information using both server authentication and data encryption to help ensure that Data is safe, secure, and available only to you. BatchBlue Software also implements an advanced security method based on dynamic data and encoded session identifications, and hosts the Site in a secure server environment that uses a firewall and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. Finally, BatchBlue Software provides unique user names and passwords that must be entered each time a customer logs on. These safeguards help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of Data.

Customers of the Service will be using the Site to host data and information (“Data”). BatchBlue Software will not review, share, distribute, print, or reference any such Data except as provided in the BatchBlue Software End User License Agreement, or as may be required by law. Individual records may at times be viewed or accessed only for the purpose of resolving a problem, support issue, or suspected violation of the End User License Agreement, or as may be required by law. Of course, customers are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password.

### Opt-Out Policy

BatchBlue Software offers its visitors and customers a means to choose how we may use information provided. If, at any time after registering for information or ordering the Service, you change your mind about receiving information from us or about sharing your information with third parties, send us a request specifying your new choice. Simply send your request to support@batchblue.com.

### Correcting & Updating Your Information

If customers need to update or change registration information they may do so by editing the user or organization record. To update a User Profile, log on to BatchBlue Software and select Setup to add or update information. To update Organization’s data, log on to BatchBlue Software and select Organization Setup. To update billing information please email support@batchblue.com or call 1-888-40-BATCH(22824). To discontinue the Service and to have data returned, email support@batchblue.com or call 1-888-40-BATCH(22824). BatchBlue Software will respond to your correction or update request within at most 30 days from the date of your request.

Customers can update or remove their personal information at any time by logging into the Website and editing their Personal Information within Setup. Customers can view their updated profile to confirm their edits have been made.

### Additional Information

Questions regarding this Statement or the practices of this Site should be directed to BatchBlue Software’s Security Administrator by e-mailing such questions to admin@batchblue.com or by regular mail addressed to BatchBlue Software, LLC, 11 South Angell Street #422, Providence, RI 02906 Attn: Security Administrator.

### California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits Site visitors who are California residents and who have provided us with “personal information” (as that term is defined in Section 1798.83) to request certain information about the disclosure of that information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, you may contact us by writing to: BatchBlue Software, LLC, 11 South Angell Street #422, Providence, RI 02906 Attn: Security Administrator.

### Notice to Visitors Outside the United States

You should be aware that the United States and other countries have not harmonized their privacy regulations. Because BatchBlue and its servers are located in the United States and our services are directed towards the United States market, our Privacy Policy has been prepared to comply with applicable United States regulations. By accessing and/or using the Site or our services and providing personal information to us through the Site, you agree to the level of privacy protection set out in this Privacy Policy. If you use the hosted version of Batchbook to collect and store personal information from individuals outside the United States, you are responsible for compliance with all applicable data protection laws, including providing required notices and obtaining consents to transfer of that information to BatchBlue in the United States. If you cannot comply with these obligations, please do not use Batchbook.

### “Do Not Track”

“Do Not Track” is a standard that is currently under development. Because it is not yet finalized, BatchBook adheres to the standards in this policy and does not monitor or follow any Do Not Track browser requests.

### Notices and Revisions

Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Notice may change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our Site frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We will not make material changes to our policies and practices to make them less protective of Your Information collected in the past under prior policies without your consent.

### Previous Privacy Policy

Our previous policy expires completely on April 30th, 2018 for all accounts. [View it here](http://batchbook.com/privacy-old/). New accounts should refer to the privacy policy above.
